let set8=
[
    {
        question:`1. United Nations celebrate world water day on?`,
        options:
        [
            'A. March 22',
'B. April 22',
'C. March 20',
'D. May 22',

        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Answer: A
        Explanation:
         22nd March is celebrated as the World Water Day; to attract the
        attention of everybody towards the importance of conserving
        water.
         The amount of water recommended by the United Nations for
        drinking, washing, cooking and maintaining proper hygiene is a
        minimum of 50 litres per person per day.
         Year 2003 was observed as the International Year of Freshwater
        to make people aware of this dwindling natural resource.
         World Water Day, March 22, 2005 was sponsored by the United
        Nations and focused attention on this precious and increasingly
        scarce commodity. World Water Day also marked the beginning of
        the International Decade for Action on Water for Life, during
        which the U.N. had seeked to spotlight the need to care for
        water resources and clean water.
         A major goal of the program was to halve the number of people
        without access to safe drinking water and basic sanitation by
        2015.
         World Water Day, March 2015 carried the theme of 'Water and
        Sustainable Development', providing an essential opportunity to
        highlight the role of freshwater in the sustainable development
        agenda that States were shaping to follow 2015.
        `
    },
    {
        question:`2. Consider the following —
        1. Evaporation
2. Transpiration
3. Condensation
Which of the above is/are responsible for the transformation of
water droplets forming on the surface of a glass full of ice?
`,
        options:
        ['A. 1 and 2 only',
        'B. 2 and 3 only',
        'C. 3 only',
        'D. 1, 2 and 3',
        
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Answer: C
        Explanation:
         The process of transformation of water vapour into its liquid
        form is called condensation.
         Tiny droplets of water on the surface of a glass containing ice are
        formed due to condensation. Air contains water vapour, and when
        air comes in contact with a cold surface, the water vapour cools
        down and condenses to form droplets of water.
         Evaporation and transpiration, both change water from liquid to
        vapour.
        `
    },
    {
        question:`3. Consider the following statements regarding water cycle:
        1. Water enters the air through evaporation and condensation.
        2. Transpiration plays an important role in bringing the water back to
        the earth’s surface.
        3. Water present in the air forms clouds and reach the surface of
        the earth in the form of rain, snow and hail.
        Which of the statements given above is/are correct?
        `,
        options:
        [
            'A. 1 and 2 only',
'B. 2 only',
'C. 3 only',
'D. 1, 2 and 3',

        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Answer: C
        Explanation:
         Water enters the atmosphere through evaporation and and
        transpiration. For water cycle, water vapour must be present in
        the atmosphere.
         Condensation plays a major role in bringing the water back to the
        earth’s surface, while through transpiration, water enters the
        atmosphere.
         In the atmosphere, water remains in the form of clouds. This
        water reaches the earth’s surface in the form of rain, snow and
        hail.
         In the last step, water reaches the oceans through the rivers and
        streams. This is how the water cycle is completed. It is
        responsible for maintaining a fixed volume of water on earth.
        `
    },
    {
        question:`4. Which of the following are not the liquid forms of water?
        A. Snow
B. Lake water
C. River water
D. Water vapour
E. Ice
Choose the correct options :
`,
        options:
        [
            'A. 1, 4 and 5',
            'B. 1 and 2',
            'C. 2 and 3',
            'D. 4 only',
            
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Answer: A`
    },
    {
        question:`5. The number of g-molecule of oxygen in 6.02 x 1024CO molecules is`,
        options:
        [
            'A. 1 gram of molecule',
            'B. 0.5 gram of molecule',
            'C. 5 gram of molecule',
            'D. 10 gram of molecule',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Answer: C
        5 gram of molecule
        1 mole CO equivalent to 6.02x1023 molecules of CO contain 6.02x1023 atoms of Oxygen. 
        So 6.02x1024 CO molecules contain 6.02x1024 atoms of O which is equivalent to 10 gm-atoms of oxygen. 
        Since Oxygen is diatomic, 
        10 g-atom = 12x10g-molecule of Oxygen = 5 gram-molecule of O2 = 5 grams of O2 molecule.`
    },
    {
        question:`6. Seas and oceans are full of water on earth. However, a
        very small percentage of water present on earth is available for
        us. This percentage is roughly:`,
        options:
        ['A. 0.006%.',
        'B. 0.06%.',
        'C. 0.6%.',
        'D. 6%.',
        
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Answer: A
        Explanation: About 72 percent of the Earth's surface is watercovered, and the oceans hold about 96.5 percent of all Earth's
        water. Water also exists in the air as water vapor, in rivers and
        lakes, in icecaps and glaciers, in the ground as soil moisture and in
        aquifers, and even in .Freshwater makes up a very small fraction of
        all water on the planet. While nearly 70 percent of the world is
        covered by water, only 2.5 percent of it is fresh. The rest is saline
        and ocean-based. Even then, just 1 percent of our freshwater is
        easily accessible, with much of it trapped in glaciers and snowfields.
        Some 72 percent of Earth is covered in water, but 97 percent of
        that is salty ocean water and not suitable for drinking.The rest are
        in the form of lakes ,etc.So the percentage remaining available for
        us is 0.006 %.
        `
    },
    {
        question:`7. Every Drop Counts” is a slogan related to`,
        options:
        ['A. counting of drops of any liquid.',
        'B. counting of water drops.',
        'C. importance of water.',
        'D. importance of counting.',
        
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Answer: C`
    },
    {
        question:`8. Which of the following things should be present in drinking water?`,
        options:
        ['A. Suspended impurities',
        'B. Dissolved gases like O2&CO2',
        'C. Germs and bacteria',
        'D. All of these',
        
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Answer: B`
    },
    {
        question:`9. Which of the following is a traditional method of collecting water?`,
        options:
        [
            'A. Bawari',
'B. well',
'C. canal',
'D. tank',

        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Answer: A
        Explantion: Bawri is a traditional method. it is a step-well in which
        rainwater is reserved or stored to supply water to people during
        droughts. Bawris, are wells or ponds in which the water may be
        reached by descending a set of steps. They may be covered and
        protected and are often of architectural significance.
        `
    },
    {
        question:`10. The process of recharging ground water using rain water is called`,
        options:
        [
            'A. drip irrigation',
'B. water harvesting',
'C. Bawri',
'D. Infiltration',

        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Answer: B
        Explanation: Watering harvesting means capturing rain water,
        where it falls and capture the runoff from, catchment and streams
        etc. Generally, water harvesting is direct rainwater collection. This
        collected water could be stored for later use and recharged into the
        ground water again. Rain is primary water source lakes, ground water
        and rivers are the secondary water source.
        Rainwater could be easily collected in plastic tanks. They are easy to
        install and handle. They are comparatively cheap from underground
        tanks, but definitely take up space. For harvesting rain water you
        first calculate the possible rain, you can do this by getting
        information from Meteorological Bureau of your area. They would
        give you information about the average rainfall during whole
        month.For instance if you have 600mm rains every year and the area
        of your roof is 200 square meters, and you are interested to catch
        the whole area for one month storage. Your tank volume must be
        10,000 liters. This quantity of water will give 10,000/30 about 33
        liters water per day.
        Water harvesting can be undertaken through a variety of ways
        1. Capturing runoff from rooftops
        2. Capturing runoff from local catchments
        3. Capturing seasonal floodwaters from local streams
        4. Conserving water through watershed management
        `
    }
]